roia.biz 2013-04-14

# Privacy | TrackingSoft

### Privacy Statement

Protecting your privacy is important to TrackingSoft. We hope the following policy will help you understand how TrackingSoft collects, uses, and safeguards the personal information you provide on our website and the information gathered on behalf of the clients of our advertisement tracking platform.

### Information Collection

When you browse our website, you do so anonymously. We don’t collect personal information, including your name, phone number, or email address. We do log your IP address (the Internet address of your computer) to give us an idea of which parts of our website you visit and how long you spend there. But we do not link your IP address to anything personally identifiable. The only other information automatically provided to us is the type of computer and operating system you are using. Your browser supplies us with this information.

Like many other commercial websites, the TrackingSoft website may use a standard technology called a “cookie” to collect information about how you use the site. This cookie information is intended to determine repeat visit statistics. This information is not shared or otherwise used.

In some of our advertising on other web sites, we use a device called a “click-through URL.” When you click on one of these URLs, you pass through our system before arriving at a page on our site that is your true destination. TrackingSoft uses click-throughs to determine the level of interest in particular topics and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising. We do not share this data, and we make no attempt to match click-throughs to any personally identifiable information.

### Advertising Platform Information Collection

Trackingsoft provides multiple methods of tracking for sites which utilize our tracking services. Information captured by use of these methods includes the details of the ads displayed to and/or clicked by you. No personally identifiable information (including name, address, email, or phone number) is captured or stored in this process. The tracking technologies implemented and used as part of our tracking service include:

  * **Cookies** – A cookie is a small file that is stored by your web browser on your computer’s hard drive. These are used as part of our tracking service to store information on what ad was seen and/or clicked and the date and time of your interaction with the ad.
  * **Specialized links** – Click-through URLs are special links used within ads. When you click one of these links, you pass through our system before arriving at the true destination page. This allows us to calculate of the number of clicks on each ad for the purpose of measuring the effectiveness of the advertising.
  * **Web beacons** – Sometimes referred to as pixels or page tags, beacons are tracking codes placed on web pages that notify our servers when a specific page has been loaded. Typically these are placed on a confirmation page simply to indicate that a referred visitor has completed an action (purchase or form submission) on the site. Used in conjunction with cookies, beacons allow the tracking of which ads result in an action being completed by a visitor.

### Information Use

If you provide us with personal information, or have done so in the past, we may attempt to contact you to determine if our software met your expectations, offer additional assistance or notify you about special offers. If you do not want us to contact you, you can choose to “opt out”. TrackingSoft will respect your wishes.

Information gathered by our tracking platform is used for statistical purposes to determine the effectiveness of advertising campaigns and individual advertisements. If you wish not to be tracked as part a part of this service, you may “opt-out” of cookie tracking and we will not store your interactions with any advertisements displayed as part of this service.

### Data Storage Period

TrackingSoft configures all cookies to expire a maximum of 1 year after the last click on a link used for tracking. Additionally, web server logs are maintained for 3 months.

### Opting Out

**Emails** – Although most customers tell us they appreciate receiving our mailings, we recognize the importance of providing you with choices. At any time, you may request to discontinue mailings from us by simply replying to the email and informing us of your preferences or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of every message. With the exception of support case correspondence, which is customer initiated, all of our email messages clearly explain how you can easily opt out and stop receiving such messages from us.

**Cookies** – TrackingSoft respects your wishes when it comes to tracking and provides a simple procedure to prevent the use of tracking cookies.

**Current optout status:** TS:  IM: 

To opt-out of allowing the use of tracking cookies, please click here. Please note that this opt-out uses a cookie to store your request and may need to be redone if you delete or block your cookies or if you switch browser or computer. If you would like to opt back in, this can be completed by deleting your cookies.

### Data Security

TrackingSoft is fully committed to data security. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place managerial and commercially appropriate electronic procedures to safeguard and secure the information you provide to us and that is gathered online.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy please feel to [contact us](http://trackingsoft.com/about-us/contact-us/ "Contact Us").

### Company Commitment to Privacy

We believe strongly in respecting your privacy. However, we also reserve the right to change our privacy policy in order to adapt to new situations. Our commitment is to inform users how we intend to use any information we request before it is collected (so you can opt in), and to respect your wishes to opt out.

TrackingSoft’s website contains links to other websites and is not responsible for privacy practices of those websites. TrackingSoft encourages users to learn about the privacy practices of those websites.
